I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
-I'm thinking of quitting this life.
-Is it because of a woman?
Yeah, well...
Tanaka-kun! Tanaka-kun!
（女子生徒）田中(たなか)君 田中君！
（コユキ）あっ えーと…
Uhh...
Page 31.
ページ:page
（田辺(たなべ)）31ページだぞ フッ
サンキュー:thank you
（コユキ）あ… サンキュー
Thanks.
"Classical Japanese"
"The color of the flowers
of the twin sal trees
沙羅[しゃら, さら]:sal (tree) (Shorea robusta)/saul|Japanese stewartia (Stewartia pseudocamellia), 双樹[そうじゅ]:two trees|sal (tree) (Shorea robusta)/saul, 花[はな]:flower|cherry blossom|beauty||, 色[いろ]:colour|complexion|appearance||, 色[しょく]:counter for colours
（コユキ）
“沙羅双樹(さらそうじゅ)の花の色—”
"Classical Japanese"
is a manifestation of the saying,
"All that prosper must decline."
盛者必衰[しょうしゃひっすい, しょうじゃひっすい]:Even the prosperous inevitably decay (from the Humane King Sutra)/sic transit gloria mundi, 理[り]:reason|general principle (as opposed to individual concrete phenomenon)|(in neo-Confucianism) the underlying principles of the cosmos, 理[ことわり]:reason/truth/way of things, あらわす:to represent/to signify|to reveal, あらわす:to write/to publish
“盛者必衰(じょうしゃひっすい)の 理(ことわり)をあらわす…”
"Classical Japanese"
Good for you, Tanaka!
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger
（教師）さすがだ 田中
However, this is your English period.
英語[えいご]:English (language)
しかし… 今は英語の時間だ
静か[しずか]:quiet|slow|calm
（教師）はーい 静かにー！
Quiet down!
（田辺）やるな！
ハァ…
毎日[まいにち]:every day, 続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||
（コユキ）いつまで
こんな毎日が続くんだろう…
How long is this life going to continue?
人生[じんせい]:(human) life (i.e. conception to death), 歳[さい]:-years-old|ability/gift, 歳[とし]:year|age|past one's prime, 袋小路[ふくろこうじ]:blind alley/cul-de-sac/impasse
俺の人生は 14歳にして
袋小路の中にあった
At the age of 14,
my life was at a dead end.
そうだ—
That is...until I met him.
あの人に 会うまでは…
"Live 1: The View at Fourteen"
生徒会[せいとかい]:student council, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
（アナウンス）
生徒会からの連絡です
"Live 1: The View at Fourteen"
This is a message from
your Student Council.
The equipment used by the
various clubs should be stored-
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 部活[ぶかつ]:club activities, 使用[しよう]:use/application/employment, 備品[びひん]:fixtures/furnishings/equipment
最近 部活に使用した備品の…
The equipment used by the
various clubs should be stored-
Tanabe, did you read that article?
読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
（コユキ）田辺もアレ読んだ？
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 大リーグ[だいリーグ]:the major leagues, 首位打者[しゅいだしゃ]:the leading hitter
ああ すごいよなー
大リーグで首位打者だもんなー
Yeah. Isn't that something?
The first batter up,
and in the major league, too!
（コユキ）だよなー
Yeah...
The way our lives have been,
毎日[まいにち]:every day
ハァ こんな毎日じゃ—
we'll never be able to write
an interesting autobiography.
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant, 自伝[じでん]:autobiography, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
俺たち面白い自伝なんか
書けないよね
Hey, Tanaka...
自伝[じでん]:autobiography, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
おい 田中～
お前 自伝書くために生きてんの？
Are you living your life
to write an autobiography?
Of course not. But...
（コユキ）そんなわけじゃ
ないけどさ… でもさ…
Let's enjoy life! C'mon!
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 人生[じんせい]:(human) life (i.e. conception to death), 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
楽しい人生 送ろーぜ！ ほらっ
（コユキ）えっ？ おい 田辺～っ
Hey, Tanabe!
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 部員[ぶいん]:staff/member (club, society, etc.), ったら:indicates supposition/if ... then|(typically after someone's name) indicates exasperation
（女子部員１）
もー 吉田(よしだ)君ったら！
-C'mon, Yoshida-kun!
-Have you gained weight, Kazuko?
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 部員[ぶいん]:staff/member (club, society, etc.), 和子[わこ]:son of a person of high social standing, 太る[ふとる]:to grow fat (stout, plump)/to become fat/to gain weight
（女子部員２）
和子(かずこ) ちょっと太ったんじゃない？
Listen, I shortened my
100-meter time by two seconds!
メートル:metre/meter, タイム:time, 秒[びょう]:second (60th min), 縮める[ちぢめる]:to shorten|to crumple (fabric)|to make (one's body) smaller
（男子部員）俺 100メートルの
タイムさ ２秒も縮めちったよー
I found this great shaved ice shop.
Why don't we go?
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 部員[ぶいん]:staff/member (club, society, etc.), おいしい:delicious/tasty|attractive, アイス:ice, 店[みせ]:store/shop/establishment, 店[てん]:-store/-shop, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
（女子部員３）私 おいしい
アイスの店 見つけたんだ
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 員[いん]:member, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
（女子部員４）キャーッ
かけないでよね！
Don't splash me!
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently
今度 行かない？
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 員[いん]:member, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
（女子部員４）キャーッ
かけないでよね！
へへへへっ…
おー いいねっ これっ
Oh, this is great!
This is good! It's good! It's good!
いいよ いいよ いいよ！
お～っ！
Oh! It's Ishiguro-sempai!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
石黒(いしぐろ)先輩だ！
（コユキ）えっ…
ビューティー:beauty, フェイス:face, ダイナマイト:dynamite, ボディー:body
（田辺）ビューティーフェイスに
ダイナマイトボディー
A beautiful face and dynamite body!
スポーツ:sport/sports, 万能[ばんのう, まんのう]:all-purpose/utility|almighty, 成績[せいせき]:results/record/grades, 常[とこ]:constant/unchanging/eternal, 常[ただ, タダ]:ordinary|free of charge|unaffected||, トップ:top
スポーツ万能なうえに
成績も常にトップ10(テン)！
A great athlete and her grades
are always in the top ten!
Izumi Ishiguro's the perfect
Miss Higashi Middle School!
完璧[かんぺき, かんべき]:perfect/complete/flawless, 泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
完璧なミス東(ひがし)中 石黒 泉(いずみ)！
She gets me hot all over! I can't stand it!
ハッと:taken aback|suddenly (realizing, understanding, becoming aware, etc.)|quickly (of actions, changes, etc.)|, グッとくる:to touch emotionally/to feel something/to strike home, たまる:to collect/to gather/to save, たまる:to be saved up (e.g. money)
ハッとしてグッとくんね～
たまんねぇ～
-You're next!
-Okay!
Okay...I'm gonna snap away...
よーし:alright/all right/right on, 撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film), まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly
（田辺）
よーし 撮りまくって…
I'll sell 'em all and make me a fortune!
売る[うる]:to sell, まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly, 財産[ざいさん]:property/fortune/assets, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
売りまくって ひと財産作るぞっ
おほほ～ ほほほほっ
お… おっ？
Hey! What are you doing?!
お～い 何だよ お前
I see. You want to take some too?
Is that it?
撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film)
そっか お前も撮りたいんだよな
そーなんだよな ハハハッ…
Back then, Izumi-chain was
the first person to talk to me.
（コユキ）あの時—
初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ..., 声をかける[こえをかける]:to greet/to call out to someone, 泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
初めて声をかけてくれたのは
泉ちゃんだった…
"Thank you for your years of patronage.
Nakajima Calligraphy School"
"Tenant Wanted"
-Izumi-chan...
-Give it back!
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
（コユキ）“泉ちゃん”
３年前までは そう呼んでいたんだ
返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
（田辺）返せよー
Until three years ago,
that's what I called her.
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
（コユキ）“泉ちゃん”
３年前までは そう呼んでいたんだ
（女子部員）
ああっ！ 誰かいるー！
Someone's over there!
See?! There are two guys over there!
あそこ:there (place physically distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|genitals, 男子[だんし]:youth/young man
（女子部員）
ほら あそこに男子が２人！
Who are they?! 7th graders?!
（男子部員）
誰だ おい！ １年なのか？
Somebody you know, Izumi?
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
泉の知り合い？
-They had a camera, those two.
-Catch them!
カメラ:camera, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
カメラ持ってたわよ あの２人
よーし:alright/all right/right on, 捕まえる[つかまえる]:to catch/to arrest/to seize
（男子部員）
よーし 捕まえろ！
（泉）コユキ…
Koyuki?
（コユキ）ハァ… ハァ…
いやー バッチリ見られちゃったな
俺たち…
Man, they got a good look at us.
ゲーセン:game center/game centre
さっ ゲーセン行くぞ！
Come on. Let's go to the game center.
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
田中～ 早く来いよー
Hurry up, Tanaka!
（女子高生）
フフッ フフフ… やだ もう！
Hey, stop that!
Get lost!
ウザい:annoying/noisy|strict
（女の子）ウザい
男の子[おとこのこ, おとこのコ]:boy/male child/baby boy, 男の子[おのこ]:man/boy
（男の子１）よし いくぞ こうだ！
（男の子２）あ～
Yeah, that's it! Go!
サンキュー:thank you
（田辺）おっ サンキュー
Thanks!
Did it! The Golden Bat!
よーし:alright/all right/right on
（田辺）よーし！
ゴールデンバットだぜ！
-Wanna eat a beef bowl?
-I'll pass. I'm broke.
牛丼[ぎゅうどん]:rice covered with beef and vegetables, 食う[くう]:to eat|to live|to bite||, 金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal
（田辺）牛丼 食ってく？
（コユキ）俺パス 金ないし
I see. See ya!
（田辺）そっか じゃーな
This place seems a little iffy...
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
何か… ヤバそう…
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
Whaddya want?!
（男性）んだぁっ こらぁ！
（コユキ）うわーっ う… いってぇ
Ouch...
あ…
（男性）ヒヒヒヒヒッ… おらっ
Oww...
（コユキ）いっつつつつ～…
ハァ… 俺…
Man...
What am I doing?
何してんだろ…
Oww!
いっつ… いいっ…
子ども[こども]:child/children, 逃がす[にがす]:to set free/to let go|to miss (e.g. a chance)
（子ども１）逃がすなー！
Yay! Now it's my turn! Hold him!
子ども[こども]:child/children, 捕まえる[つかまえる]:to catch/to arrest/to seize
（子ども２）
そっちだ そっちだ 捕まえろ！
You can't get away from us!
子ども[こども]:child/children, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however
（子ども３）
どこ行ったってムダなんだよ
Wait!
Damn!
What's with that dog?!
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
何だ？ あの犬…
Hey, what are you doing?
Quit tormenting the dog!
お おい 何してんだ？
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, いじめる:to tease/to torment/to persecute
やめろよ いじめるのは
子ども[こども]:child/children
（子ども１）うっせーな！
みんな 行こうぜ！
Aw, shut up! Let's get outta here!
Yeah!
子ども[こども]:child/children
（子ども２）おう！
（子ども３）んっ
（竜介(りゅうすけ)）ベック！ カムヒア！
Beck! Come here!
I told you, you shouldn't go out alone.
You...You made me worried.
That guy's...a foreigner?
外国[がいこく, そとぐに]:foreign country
（コユキ）外国… の… 人？
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
（竜介）ハッハ～
気持ち悪いだろ この犬
Doesn't this dog look weird?
No, no...Not bad dog...
ドッグ:dog, 日本人[にほんじん, にっぽんじん]:Japanese person/Japanese people
（コユキ）ノーノー！ ノーバット
ドッグ… え… 日本人？
Huh? You're Japanese?
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（竜介）
ありがとう ベック助けてくれて
Thanks for saving Beck.
（コユキ）あ… ワンちゃん
おいでー ワンちゃん
Doggy...Come here, doggy.
Good boy...
よーし:alright/all right/right on
よーし よーし…
うっ！ うわあっ！
Uh-uh. You shouldn't put your hand out
to a frightened dog.
おびえる:to become frightened/to be frightened (of)/to be scared (of), 犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|, いきなり:abruptly/suddenly/all of a sudden, 手を出す[てをだす]:to turn one's hand to|to get involved in|to start a fight
んっんっ おびえてる犬の前に
いきなり手を出すのはダメだ
-Use these.
-Thanks.
使い[つかい]:errand|messenger|familiar spirit|, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（竜介）使いな
（コユキ）あっ ありがとう
See ya.
じゃあな
"Onochin Loans"
(This is a pack of tissues)
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
これ 今度お返ししまーす！
I'll return this to you next time!
Is that for real?
実話[じつわ]:true story
（田辺）それ実話？
（コユキ）うん
Yeah. First I get punched,
and then I get bitten...What a day!
殴る[なぐる]:to strike/to hit/to beat, さんざん:thoroughly/completely|severely, さんざん:three mountains|three shrines (of Kumano)
殴られるわ かまれるわで
さんざんだったよ
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is
マジかよ ひでーな そりゃ
No way...That's awful!
That weird dog...I hope
it doesn't have rabies.
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||, 犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|, 狂犬病[きょうけんびょう]:rabies/hydrophobia
あの変な犬
狂犬病 大丈夫かな
Hey! There's someone here
to see you, Tanaka!
おーい:hey!/oi!|I, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（男子生徒）
おーい！ 田中に お客さん…
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（女子生徒）石黒先輩だ！
It's Ishiguro-sempai!
Uhh...Don't let them bother you.
気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry
（コユキ）何か… 気にしないで
Listen, are you free on Saturday, Koyuki?
土曜[どよう]:Saturday, 空く[すく]:to become less crowded/to thin out|to be hungry, 空く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
（泉）あのさー
コユキって 土曜空いてる？
Huh?!
ケンカ:quarrel/brawl/fight
どうしたの？ ケンカ？
What happened? You get into a fight?
It's nothing. I'm perfectly fine now.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
大丈夫… もう全然平気
Listen, Koyuki...
あのさ コユキ…
There was another boy
with the same name as me,
書道[しょどう]:calligraphy, 教室[きょうしつ]:classroom|department|single-room school, 同姓[どうせい]:same surname, 同名[どうめい, どうみょう]:same name|homonym
（コユキ）書道教室には
同姓同名の田中幸雄君がいた
Yukio Tanaka, in our calligraphy class.
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 命名[めいめい]:naming/christening
そこで泉ちゃんが
俺をコユキと命名した
So Izumi-chan gave me
the nickname Koyuki.
(Ko - little)
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
だから泉ちゃんは
俺をコユキって呼ぶんだ
That's why she calls me Koyuki.
"Koyuki"
I'm going bowling with some friends.
Won't you come with us?
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, ボウリング:bowling (esp. tenpin)
友達と
ボウリングやるんだけどさ—
コユキも来ない？
（コユキ）うん
Yeah...
人数[にんずう, ひとかず]:the number of people|many people/a large number of people, 確保[かくほ]:guarantee/maintain/ensure
よかったー これで人数確保
Oh, good. Now we have enough people.
It's almost exam time, so it's
hard getting everyone to join in.
試験[しけん]:examination/exam|trial, 近い[ちかい]:near|close (in time)|close (relationship)||, なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb), 参加[さんか]:participation
試験近いから みんな なかなか
参加してくれないんだもん
I didn't want to waste
the coupon Kayo-chan gave me.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, 券[けん]:ticket/coupon/bond
せっかくカヨちゃんから
もらった券 ムダにしたくないんだ
Koyuki...Thanks.
ありがと:Thank you
コユキ ありがと！
（コユキ）うん！
Yeah...
次[つぎ]:next/following|stage, 次[じ]:next|hypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)|order, 体育[たいいく]:physical education/gymnastics/athletics
あっ 私 次 体育なんだ
Oh, I have P.E. Next. See you Saturday!
土曜[どよう]:Saturday
じゃあ 土曜に！
I can't believe it...
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
信じられない…
本当にな
You're telling me...
-You seem to be happy.
-Yeah, well...
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
（コユキの母）
あら 何か楽しそうね
（コユキ）あ… ちょっと…
-Don't stay out too late, now!
-I won't.
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
（コユキの母）
あんまり遅くならないのよ
（コユキ）はーい
The uptown-bound train
will be pulling in to track two.
間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 番[ばん]:number (in a series)|(one's) turn|watch|, 番[つがい]:(one) pair (e.g. of birds)/brace|joint, 線[せん]:line|line (e.g. telephone line)|ray (e.g. X-ray)||, 上る[あがる]:to rise|to enter (esp. from outdoors)|to enter (a school)||, 上る[のぼる]:to ascend|to ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun)|to go to (the capital)||, 列車[れっしゃ]:train (ordinary), 参る[まいる]:to go|to be defeated|to be annoyed||
（アナウンス）間もなく
２番線に上り列車が参ります
Please wait behind the yellow line.
危ない[あぶない]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain||, 黄色い[きいろい]:yellow|high-pitched (voice)/shrill, 線[せん]:line|line (e.g. telephone line)|ray (e.g. X-ray)||, 下がる[さがる]:to come down|to hang|to move back||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
危ないですから
黄色い線まで お下がりください
黄色い[きいろい]:yellow|high-pitched (voice)/shrill, 線[せん]:line|line (e.g. telephone line)|ray (e.g. X-ray)||, 下がる[さがる]:to come down|to hang|to move back||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
黄色い線まで お下がりください！
Wait behind the yellow line!
Yay! I got a strike!
ストライク:strike (e.g. in baseball, bowling)
イェーイ！ ストライクだぜっ！
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ナイス:nice, 泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
ウフッ
（先輩１）ナイス！ 泉ちゃん
Nice, Izumi-chan!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 勝負[しょうぶ]:victory or defeat/match/contest
（先輩２）
もう！ 勝負にならないわよ
We'll never win at this rate!
Come on, Izumi. Let's switch teams.
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, チーム:team, 変える[かえる]:to change/to alter|to reform
ねえ 泉～ チーム変えない？
Koyuki...
（泉）コユキ！
手前[てまえ]:before|one's standpoint|we|, 手前[てめえ]:you (used by young males)|oneself, 印[いん]:seal|mudra (symbolic hand gesture)|India, 印[しるし]:mark|symbol|badge||, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at, 投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat
手前の印を狙って投げてみな
Try aiming at those marks in front of you.
（コユキ）えいっ！
Yay! Alright!
イェイ:yay, よーし:alright/all right/right on
イェイ！ よーし！
Pretty good advice, don't you think?
アドバイス:advice
どうだ 私のアドバイス！
Oh, no. It's me...My talent.
いやいや:no!/no no!/no, not at all, いやいや:unwillingly/grudgingly|shaking head in refusal (to children), 才能[さいのう]:talent/ability
いやいや 才能 才能！
Yay!
じゃん:isn't it
（コユキ）イェーイ！
（泉）へぇー コユキ やるじゃん！
You're pretty good, Koyuki!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（先輩３）おっしゃー
-Yes!
-Good job!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（先輩１）やるぅ
At that moment, the two years
we hadn't seen each other...
年間[ねんかん]:years (period of), ブランク:blank/blank space
（コユキ）その時 俺たちの
２年間のブランクは—
...vanished completely.
完全[かんぜん]:perfection/completeness, 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
完全に消えていた
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 腹[はら]:abdomen|womb|one's mind||, 減る[へる]:to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate
（先輩１）あー 腹減ったー
Boy, am I hungry!
-Let's go to McDonald's!
-How about Mr. Donut?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, マック:Mac
（先輩２）ねぇ マック行こうよ
（先輩３）ミスドも よくない？
I'd rather have a Yoshinoya beef bowl.
吉[きち, きつ]:good fortune (esp. omikuji fortune-telling result)/good luck/auspiciousness, 牛[うし, ぎゅう]:cattle (Bos taurus)|beef|Chinese "Ox" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)
（コユキ）あ 俺… 吉牛(よしぎゅう)
-Huh?!
What do I want?
（泉）私は何がいいかなー
I'll go by myself...
別行動[べつこうどう]:doing something separately (from the group)/going off on one's own
（コユキ）
俺… 別行動ってことで…
Oh! Kayo-chan!
あっ！ カヨちゃん！
Kayo-chan!
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
カヨちゃーん！
（カヨ）ん？ おー 泉っち！
Oh, Izumichi!
Yeah!
イェーイ
What are you doing?
何してんのさ
We're trying to decide whether
to go to McDonald's or Yoshinoya.
マック:Mac, 吉[きち, きつ]:good fortune (esp. omikuji fortune-telling result)/good luck/auspiciousness, 牛[うし, ぎゅう]:cattle (Bos taurus)|beef|Chinese "Ox" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)
（泉）これからマックか吉牛
行こうかなーって
McDonald's!
マック:Mac
マック！
I'm not hungry. Let's go somewhere else.
おなか:belly/abdomen/stomach
おなか すいてないし
別んとこ行こうぜ フッ
Kayo-chan, you're reeking of alcohol...
酒臭い[さけくさい]:reeking of liquor/smelling of alcohol, ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter)
（泉）カヨちゃん 酒臭い！
（カヨ）ハハハ…
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
（女性１）アレ いいらしいよ
-I hear it's pretty good.
-No way...
男性[だんせい]:man/male|masculine gender
（男性１）マジかよ
（男性２）ヒヒヒ…
Oh, come on...
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender
（女性２）やーねぇ
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（先輩３）
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ…
イェイ:yay
（泉）イェイ！
Yay!
（カヨ）フーッ しょっと…
（コユキ）うう… うあっ
飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||
飲んでるかー コユキ君！
Are you drinking, Koyuki-kun?
Yes. I'm on my second glass
of oolong tea.
ウーロン:oolong (tea), 茶[ちゃ]:tea|tea plant (Camellia sinensis)|tea preparation||, 杯[さかずき, さかづき]:sake cup/cup for alcoholic beverages, 杯[はい, はた]:sake cup|counter for cupfuls|counter for ships, octopuses and squid, 突入[とつにゅう]:rushing into/breaking into|plunging into (war, etc.)
はい！ ウ… ウーロン茶
２杯目突入です
カラオケ:karaoke (singing to taped accompaniment)
ん… みんなでカラオケ行くか？
Shall we all go for karaoke?
I'll pass. I've never been to a
karaoke place, and I'm out of money.
あー 俺パス
カラオケ:karaoke (singing to taped accompaniment), 金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal
カラオケ行ったことないし
金もないし…
ふーん:hmm/well ...|roughly
（カヨ）ふーん
But Izumichi was raving
about your singing...
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 歌[うた]:song|classical Japanese poetry (esp. tanka)|modern poetry, 褒める[ほめる]:to praise/to admire/to speak well of someone
泉っちがコユキ君の歌
褒めてたんだけどなー
Here you go! It's on the house, kids!
若者[わかもの]:young man/young woman/young people, サービス:service/help/assistance
（ミッちゃん）
ほらっ 若者たちにサービスだ
Oh, Mit-chan...Did you
have a chef's license?
（カヨ）あれ？ ミッちゃん
調理師[ちょうりし]:chef/cook, 免許[めんきょ]:license/permit/licence, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
調理師免許 持ってた？
（ミッちゃん）ねーよ そんなん
'Course not.
-What's Mit-chan-san's real name?
-Why?
ミッちゃんさんって
名前 何ていうんですか？
んー 何で？
I want to thank him,
お礼[おれい, おんれい]:thanks|manners|bow||
お礼 言いたいんですけど—
but I don't think a kid like me
should be calling him Mit-chan...
中坊[ちゅうぼう]:middle-school student, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
中坊の俺が“ミッちゃん”って
呼ぶのは… ちょっと…
Why, I don't mind you calling me Mit-chan.
かまう:to mind/to care about|to care for
なーに ミッちゃんで
かまわないよっ ヘヘッ
Thanks for the food, Mit-chan-san!
ごちそう:feast/treating (someone)|to treat (someone, e.g. to a meal)
ご ごちそうさまです
ミッちゃんさん！
You know, we have a lot of regulars,
常連[じょうれん]:regular customer/regular patron|constant companion, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
ここはな 常連さんも多いけど
誰が何やってるかなんて知らない
but none of them knows
what the others do.
They don't even know if their names
are real or just nicknames.
あだ名[あだな, こんめい]:nickname
本当の名前なのか
あだ名なのかも知らない
持ち込む[もちこむ]:to take something into ...|to lodge (a complaint)|to bring to (a state: tied game, vote, trial, etc.)
そういうもんを持ち込まないのが
「レメディ」なんだ ん？
It's Remedy's policy not
to bring problems in here.
捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up, じゃん:isn't it
（女性）うぇ～ん！ それって
私を捨てるってことじゃん！
But that means you're breaking up with me!
As I said, I don't have the time.
（竜介）だから言ってるだろ
時間がねえんだ
Oh, man...
困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
困ったな…
（女性）
うぇ～ん！ 竜介のバカ～
Damn you, Ryusuke...
He's called Ryusuke. Mature for 16.
呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||, マセる:to be precocious/to be mature for one's age/to seem grown-up, 歳[さい]:-years-old|ability/gift, 歳[とし]:year|age|past one's prime
あいつはリュースケって呼ばれてる
マセた16歳だ
-You know him?
-Uhh...no...
知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
知り合いか？
え… いえ…
He's the worst...Making girls cry,
not paying back money he owes...
泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob, 借りる[かりる]:to borrow/to have a loan|to rent, 金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
とにかくサイテー 女は泣かせる
借りた金は返さない
No way...
（コユキ）そんな…
（ミッちゃん）
でも 何ていうか こう…
But, how can I put it?
He has a strange attraction
for other people, that Ryusuke.
ひきつける:to fascinate/to attract|to have a convulsion, 不思議[ふしぎ]:wonder/miracle/strange, 魅力[みりょく]:charm/fascination/glamour
人をひきつける不思議な魅力が
あるんだよなー
竜介のヤツは…
（カヨ）んー それにさぁ あいつ
何かとハッタリが多いんだよ
-Besides, he's always bluffing.
-Mit-chan, sake!
酒[さけ, ささ]:alcohol/sake
（男性）
ミッちゃーん 酒～
（ミッちゃん）おう
（コユキ）ハッタリ？
Bluffing?
（カヨ）コユキは
「ダイブリ」って知ってる？
Koyuki, have you heard of Dying Breed?
There's this super popular band
called Dying Breed in America.
アメリカ:America, めっちゃ:very/extremely/excessively, 売れる[うれる]:to sell (well)|to be well known/to be popular
アメリカで めっちゃ売れてる—
ブリード:bleeding (e.g. dyes)/seepage, バンド:band
ダイイング・ブリードっていう
バンドがあんだけどさー
What about Dying Breed? I love them!
ダイブリが どうしたの？
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
私 大好き！
ギター:guitar, 弾く[はじく]:to flip|to repel|to use (an abacus)|, 弾く[ひく]:to play (piano, guitar), 昔[むかし]:olden days/former
あいつ ダイブリのギター弾いてる
エディと昔—
He says he used to play in a band
with Eddy, Dying Breed's guitarist.
バンド:band
バンドやってたって言うんだぜ
Who are you talking about?
ねぇ それって誰？
You idiot...
（女性）バカーッ うう…
Come on. You've got
other guys besides me.
以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting
（竜介）なんだよ お前
俺以外にも男いるだろ？
Ryusuke! Which is more important
to you?! Me or the band?!
バンド:band, どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play
（女性）竜介は 私とバンドと
どっちが大切なのさ！
The band.
バンド:band
バンド
Mit-chan-san...Would you give this to him?
渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
（コユキ）ミッちゃんさん
これ あの人に渡してください
（ミッちゃん）おう
Sure...
Wasn't it like a drama back there?
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ドラマ:drama, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（泉）
さっきの… ドラマみたいだったね
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（コユキ）うん 何かすごかった
Yeah. It was really something.
Hey!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, おーい:hey!/oi!|I
（先輩１）おーい！ おい おーい！
Hey! Hey! Come look at this!
見て見て
いやー よくここまでやるよなー
Somebody really did a job on this car.
It's gonna cost a mint to fix it.
直す[なおす]:to cure|to fix|to do over again (after -masu base of verb)||, 結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
これ直すの 結構かかるぜ
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 近づく[ちかづく, ちかずく]:to approach/to draw near|to get acquainted with
（コユキ）あ 先輩
あんまり近づかないほうが…
Sempai, I don't think
you should get too close.
What is it? Killjoy.
気分[きぶん]:feeling/mood, 壊す[こわす]:to break|to wreck|to break (a bill, etc.)
何だよー 気分壊すなぁ
Hey! What the fuck are
you doing to my car?!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 英語[えいご]:English (language), 愛車[あいしゃ]:(one's) beloved car (or motorcycle, bicycle, etc.)/(one's) wheels
（外国人１：英語）
〈おい！ お前ら俺たちの愛車に
何してんだ!?〉
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national
（外国人２）ブハァッ
Whatsa matter, you fuckers around
here speak English, or what?
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 英語[えいご]:English (language), 話せる[はなせる]:to be able to speak/to be able to talk|to be understanding
（外国人２：英語）
〈お前ら 英語 話せんのか？〉
Oh...I'm...sorry...
ソーリー:sorry
あ あ アイムソーリー…
Sempai! Why are you apologizing?!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 謝る[あやまる]:to apologize/to apologise
（コユキ）
先輩 何で謝るんですか！
W-well...
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（先輩１）いや だって…
（先輩１）うわっ
（泉たち）キャーッ
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
ん？ 帰るのか？
-You leaving?
-Yeah...
A young kid asked me to give this to you.
小僧[こぞう]:youngster|young Buddhist priest|young shopboy, 渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over
（ミッちゃん）これ 小僧が
お前に渡してくれってさ
俺に？
To me? Thanks, Mit-chan.
サンクス:thanks
サンクス ミッちゃん
Fuckin' stupid little kids!
ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of, ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 弁償[べんしょう]:reimbursement/compensation/reparation, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
〈ふざけたガキどもだ！
ちゃんと弁償してもらうぞ〉
I'm gonna make you pay
for all of this right now!
No, no. We are not guilty. We-
ノット:knot, ノット:knot (nautical mile per hour), ギルティー:guilty
（泉）ノーノー
ウィアー ノット ギルティー
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national
ウィ ドント…
（外国人２）チッチッチッ…
What are you, a rapper or a singer?
"We are the world?!"
I'll kick your ass if you don't pay!
I'm serious. Shut the...
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, ひっぱたく:to slap/to strike/to spank
〈おい ちゃんと聞いてるのか？
金ださないと ひっぱたくぜ！〉
〈このガキどもが！〉
...fuck up!
Back off, damn you!
かげん:(moon's) last quarter, かげん:lower limit|infimum
いいかげんにしろ！ このヤロー！
（泉）コユキ…
Koyuki...
Don't act big just because
you're overgrown, dumbass (baka yaro)!
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 威張る[いばる, えばる]:to put on airs/to act big/to throw one's weight about, バカヤロー:idiot
体がデカいからって威張るな
バカヤロー！
Ba...ka?
〈バカ？〉
Nobody calls me baka around here!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national
（外国人２）
〈このイカれたガキめ！〉
You little shit! I'm kicking
your fucking ass, man! Right about now!
Stop it!
英語[えいご]:English (language), やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（竜介：英語）〈やめろ！〉
I saw your car two hours ago
and it was already scratched.
そいつ:he/she|that, 犯人[はんにん]:offender/criminal
（竜介）
〈そいつらは犯人じゃない〉
傷つく[きずつく]:to be wounded|to get hurt feelings|to get damaged
〈２時間前に見た時には
もう傷ついてたぜ〉
Who the hell are you?!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 貴様[きさま]:you/you bastard|you
（外国人２）〈誰だ 貴様？〉
You should apologize to these kids.
謝る[あやまる]:to apologize/to apologise
〈お前らは
この子たちに謝るべきだ〉
What the fuck?!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 英語[えいご]:English (language), うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying
（外国人３：英語）
〈うるせーぞ この野郎！〉
謝る[あやまる]:to apologize/to apologise
〈謝るべきだ〉
Apologize.
Apologize!
あやまる:to make a mistake/to err|to mislead, あやまる:to apologize/to apologise
〈あやまれ！〉
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national
（外国人２）フンッ ハッ！
The police are right there.
ポリス:police
〈ポリスが来るぜ！〉
Shut the fuck up, kid!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying
（外国人２）〈うるせー！〉
Here, let's get somewhere else.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 移す[うつす]:to change|to change the object of one's interest or focus|to spend or take time||
（竜介）〈場所を移そうぜ〉
カモン:Come on!
（竜介）カモン
Come on!
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national
（外国人３）
〈ついて来い だとよ〉
Come on, he says...
竜介君！
Ryusuke-kun!
Never mind me. Get on home.
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
いいから早く帰れ
"Noodles"
Here are your ramen noodles.
ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame
（店員）
へいっ ラーメンお待ちっ！
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
（先輩３）おっ うまそーっ
"Noodles"
This looks good!
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ポテト:potato, 超[ちょう, チョー]:super-/ultra-|over (after a number or counter), まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful
しかし さっきのポテト
あれ超まずかったよねー
But those French fries...
Weren't they just awful?
You haven't finished your ramen.
ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame, 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
ラーメン まだ残ってるぞ
Yeah...But I really want
to eat a beef bowl!
牛[うし, ぎゅう]:cattle (Bos taurus)|beef|Chinese "Ox" constellation (one of the 28 mansions), 皿[さら]:plate|serving|kanji radical 108 (at the bottom), 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
うん でもさ… 俺 どうしても
牛皿が食べたくなったんだ
Koyuki...
コユキ…
Hey, hey-hey hey!
I-It's cool, man. It's cool.
Put that thing down, man, please.
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 落ち着く[おちつく]:to calm down|to calm down|to settle down (in a location, job, etc.)||, クール:cool (temperature, color, etc.)
（外国人２）〈落ち着けよ！
クールにやろうぜ〉
Put it down. Take it easy.
Please...
Well...Wanna try?
試す[ためす]:to attempt/to test/to try out
（竜介）〈おい 試してみるか！〉
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
〈お前の町じゃ
どうか知らんが—〉
I don't know about your town,
but my friends in New York died.
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce
〈俺がいたＮＹじゃ
死んだ友達も少なくない〉
You can't fuck around in my neighborhood.
好き勝手[すきかって]:doing whatever one pleases, させる:to make (someone) do|to allow (someone) to, させる:(usu. followed by a negative form) worth special consideration
〈ココじゃ好き勝手させないぜ！〉
Get the fuck outta here! Fucking bastard!
消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
〈ココから消えちまえ！〉
外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, 撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat
（外国人２）
〈撃つな 撃たないでくれよ〉
-No! No! Leave it!
-Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
（コユキ）ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
Ryusuke-kun!
竜介君！
Damn...Treating me like trash...
ちくしょう:beast (i.e. any animal other than man)|person reborn into the animal realm, ちくしょう:keeping a mistress (concubine), 扱い[あつかい]:treatment/service, やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
ちくしょう
人をゴミ扱いしやがって…
シット:shit
ああ… シット！
Shit!
（コユキ）ハァ… ハァ…
竜介君！ 大丈夫？
R-Ryusuke-kun! Are you all right?!
They were so drunk, I didn't
think they'd figure it out.
相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||, 酔う[よう]:to get drunk|to feel sick (e.g. in a vehicle)|to be elated, バレる:to leak out (a secret)/to be exposed (a lie, improper behaviour, etc.) (behavior)
あいつら 相当酔ってたから
バレないと思ったんだけどな…
Man...it hurts...
あ～… いてー
I was impressed.
感動[かんどう]:being deeply moved emotionally/excitement/passion
俺 感動したんだ… うっ
You're such a shorty, but you
went after those big foreigners.
小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 外人[がいじん, ほかびと]:foreigner (esp. one of European ancestry)/gaijin|outsider, 向かう[むかう]:to face|to go towards/to head towards
お前 小さいのに あんなデカい
外人に向かっていくんだもんな
ん？ どうした？
What's the matter?
Hey, hey...I'm the one
who should be crying.
おいおい:Hey!/Wait a minute!|boohoo, おいおい:gradually/by degrees/little by little, 泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob, むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat
おいおい
泣きたいのは むしろ俺だぜ
I'm sorry. But lately...
for a long time, actually,
（コユキ）ごめん…
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.)
でも 最近… ていうか
もうずっと前から—
I felt like no one cared if I lived or not.
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something
いてもいなくても…
誰も俺のことなんか…
Koyuki!
（泉）コユキー！
It's them...
あ… みんな…
Hey, you guys-
皆[みんな, みな]:all/everyone|everything
皆さん…
（泉）ケガ… 大丈夫？
-Are you all right?
-I'm just scratched up.
かすり傷[すりきず, かすりきず]:scratch/graze/abrasion
（竜介）ああ こんなん かすり傷だ
The other day, he saved my dog.
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
この前
彼に犬を助けてもらったんでね
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
（泉）犬… ですか
Your dog?
Beck is a dog Eddy and I found
when we were in a band together.
（竜介）
ベックは 俺がエディと—
バンド:band, 組む[くむ]:to cross (legs or arms)|to put together|to braid||, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing, 犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
バンドを組んでたころに
見つけた犬でね
-Oh, so that's a true story?
-Oh, sorry Koyuki-kun.
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（泉）わー その話って
本当なんですねー
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
（先輩３）
いやー すまん コユキ君
-Sorry I'm so late.
-Yeah...
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 遅れる[おくれる]:to be late/to be delayed/to fall behind schedule
（先輩３）遅れて すまん
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
私 ダイブリ大好きなんです
I love the Dying Breed!
Oh? Then why don't you come
and see our band sometime?
ふーん:hmm/well ...|roughly, 今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, バンド:band
ふーん じゃあ今度
俺たちのバンド見に来なよ
Yes! I will! That's so exciting!
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
はい 行きます！ わあ 楽しみ！
Matt of Dying Breed is really funny.
マット:mat, 面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant
ダイブリのマットって
面白れぇんだぜ
If he doesn't have a drink before
a show he can't get up on the stage.
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
いつもライブの前にさぁ—
酒[さけ, ささ]:alcohol/sake, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||, ステージ:stage, 上がる[あがる]:to rise|to enter (esp. from outdoors)|to enter (a school)||
酒飲まねえと
ステージ上がれねぇんだぜ
That looks pretty weird to me.
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
（田辺）ヤバいんじゃない？ それ
Now I'm pretty worried...
for Ishiguro-sempai.
かなり:considerably/fairly/quite, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 身[み]:body|oneself|one's place|, 身[むくろ]:(dead) body/corpse
俺… かなり心配んなってきた
石黒先輩の身が
I don't give a damn about you, though.
ま！ お前は どーでもいいけどな
So cheer up...
Sorry to keep you waiting!
（泉）ごめーん 待たせて！
This is Ryusuke-kun's address...
住所[じゅうしょ]:address (e.g. of house)/residence/domicile
竜介君とこ この住所…
Okay...Shall we barge in on him?
よーし:alright/all right/right on, 押しかける[おしかける]:to intrude on
よーし 押しかけちゃうか！
Huh? Right now?
いきなり:abruptly/suddenly/all of a sudden
え？ いきなり？
あっ ああ…
Koyuki...What kind of music
do you listen to?
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement
（泉）コユキって
どんな音楽 聞いてるの？
（コユキ）んー… 国吉(くによし)ちえみ
-Chiemi Kuniyoshi.
-Kuniyoshi? Oh, that idol singer?
アイドル:young star/young entertainer/heartthrob
（泉）くによし？
あっ あのアイドルの子？
Yeah...I'm sure she's going
to break out soon.
将来[しょうらい]:future (usually near)/prospects, 絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, ブレイク:break (rest), 間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman)
（コユキ）うん！ 将来
絶対ブレイク間違いなしだと思う
ふーん:hmm/well ...|roughly
（泉）ふーん…
I think it's this way.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（泉）何か こっちみたいよ
Maybe...
（コユキ）あ… そーかも
さんざん:thoroughly/completely|severely, さんざん:three mountains|three shrines (of Kumano), 迷う[まよう]:to lose one's way|to waver|to give into temptation|, 末[うら]:top end/tip, 末[うれ]:new shoots/new growth (of a tree)
（コユキ）そして俺たちは
さんざん迷った末に—
And, after taking a lot of wrong turns,
we finally arrived at Ryusuke-kun's home.
家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, たどりつく:to arrive at (after a struggle)/to finally reach/to find one's way to
竜介君の家に たどりついたんだ
（泉）キャッ
（コユキ）うわ…
"Fishing"
Another minute
Feelin' so fine
You turn the freeze
into warm light
Had a premonition
I've been waitin' ever since
My world comin' down
It's got me spinnin' 'round
If you really wanna fly
you gotta let go
Simply the most
big sensation
(once you're here you won't go back)
She's really pretty
One-eyed vision
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Little sister showed me
Really took me for a ride
My world comin' down
(once you're here you won't go back)
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Rock, you see, is the
vibration of the soul. Hm?
ロック:lock
（千葉(ちば)）
ロックってのはな こう—
バイブレーション:vibration
心のバイブレーション！
なわけよ うん
"Next Episode"
Rock, you see, is the
vibration of the soul. Hm?
"Next Episode"